dominos.co.uk 2016-04-03

# Privacy Policy | Domino's Pizza

We are committed to complying with the Data Protection Act 1998 and respecting the privacy rights of our customers. This privacy policy explains how we collect, store and use personal data about you when you visit our websites (dominos.co.uk and dominos.ie) and our mobile, tablet and other applications (our “ **Sites** ”). This policy applies to all our Sites regardless of how they are made available to you or accessed by you.

Please read this privacy policy carefully before you start using our Sites, as this policy will apply to your use of our Sites. We recommend that you print and retain a copy for future reference.

By accessing, browsing and using our Sites, you confirm that you accept this privacy policy and that you agree to comply with the terms. If you do not want your data to be used as set out in this privacy policy, you should not use our Sites.

Your use of our Sites, including any orders you place, is governed by our Terms and Conditions of Sale, Terms of Use and our Cookie Policy. Please take the time to read these, as they include important terms which apply to you.

## Who are we?

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the “ **Act** ”), the data controller of our Sites is Domino's Pizza UK & Ireland Limited (“ **we** ”, “ **us** ” or “ **our** ”) of 1 Thornbury, West Ashland, Milton Keynes MK6 4BB.

Domino's is a franchised business, where almost all stores are owned and operated by independent Domino’s Pizza franchisees (each a “ **Franchisee** ” and together our “ **Franchisees** ”). In this policy, references to **‘we’, ‘us’ and ‘our’ does not include our Franchisees and this policy does not apply to or cover the practices of our Franchisees.**

Each Franchisee is independently responsible for its own legal and regulatory compliance and for the operation of its own Domino’s Pizza store(s) (our “ **Store(s)** ”) and all compliance arising from any transactions with you, any products ordered by you from our Sites and any products ordered from our Stores.

When we refer to the **"Domino's Family"** we mean us together with our Franchisees.

If you would like to review the privacy policy and practices of any of our Franchisees, please visit the Store website of the relevant Franchisee (if one exists) or contact the Store directly.

What information do we collect?  
What do we do with the information we collect?  
Who do we share this information with?  
Where do we store your personal data  
Passwords  
Phishing  
How to get copies of or amend the information we have collected  
Linking  
Changes to our Privacy Policy  
How to Contact Us

## What information do we collect?

When you visit our Sites, we may collect:

  * information such as your computer’s IP address, browser type and version and anonymous information collected from cookies when you are browsing our Sites to help us understand how to improve our Sites and services to you; and
  * personal information such as your name, address, telephone number and email address as provided by you when you register to MyDomino’s or place an order with us and enter your payment card details. 

Once you register or place an order (even if you do not register with us) on our Sites, we know who you are and are able to link the information we collect about your computer activities to you.

Whenever we collect your personal data, for example, when you register or order with us, you will see the padlock symbol indicating a secure web transaction. 

## What do we do with the information we collect?

We use this information for all sorts of reasons. The main reason we use this information is to provide you with a great product, outrageously good service, value for money and to tell you about our products and services. We also use the information:

  * for processing your order and answering your queries;
  * for product development;
  * for statistical, market research, testing and survey purposes to administer our Sites and for internal operations;
  * to improve our Sites and ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and your computer;
  * to notify you about changes to our Sites or the services provided by the Domino's Family;
  * to carry out data matching with third parties such as Google in order to send you targeted advertising;
  * to measure and understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and to deliver relevant advertising to you;
  * to provide you with information and products or services we feel may interest you (where you have not otherwise opted-out of direct marketing). For more on this please see our Direct Marketing Policy).

We also engage third party payment processors to process the payment of your online order. These third party processors may store your payment card details, if you want them to, to speed up your transaction time. If you do not want to take advantage of this, please do not select this function.

We may retain copies of any correspondence you send us and we will keep your registration and order details. Any personal information that you provide to us and any information from which we can identify you, is held in accordance with the registration we have with the Information Commissioner’s Office.

## Who do we share this information with?

We may share your personal information with a purchaser or a potential purchaser of our business.

We may also share your personal information with the Domino's Family and selected third parties performing services on our behalf (such as, for example, direct marketing agents) who will only use the information to provide services that we have requested.

The types of functions that companies engaged by Domino's typically carry out include assisting us to more effectively fulfil orders; managing and conducting marketing; providing technical assistance and support and supporting marketing activities. However, those companies will only be permitted to use your personal information for the purpose of performing that particular function strictly in accordance with our instructions and not for any other purpose.

We may also share some of your personal information with certain third party companies for analytical purposes. The reason for doing so is that it allows us to understand your purchasing options and therefore allows us to, where appropriate, send you generic marketing offers which may be of most relevance to you.

We may provide your details to Google and other third party organisations to enable them to carry out a data matching exercise on our behalf. The purpose of this data matching exercise is to ascertain which of our customers also obtain services from these organisations with a view to us delivering bespoke information and marketing to you. You can opt out of participating in Google Analytics. Please visit our Cookie Policy to find out more.

In some circumstances, we may have to disclose your personal information by law, because a court or the police or other legal or regulatory enforcement agency has asked us for it.

We require all third parties that we work with to treat your personal information as confidential and to fully comply with all applicable UK data protection and consumer legislation.

## Where we store your personal data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by selected third parties operating outside the EEA engaged in, for example, the processing of your payment details. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of any data transmitted to our Sites and any transmission is at your own risk.

Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and corporate policies to safeguard and secure the information we receive.

## Passwords

You are required to create a password when you register an account with us. Creating a secure password is one of the best ways of keeping your information safe.

When deciding on your password it must be a minimum of 8 characters long and satisfy at least two of the following criteria:

  * use of an upper case character;
  * use of a lower case character;
  * use of a number; or
  * use of a special character

It must not:

  * use any part of your first name or surname;
  * use any part of your email address;
  * contain simple number sequences such as 123; or
  * use your birthday.

You should never write your passwords down anywhere, or share them with anyone, including close family members. We will never telephone you to ask for any personal information you have given online.

Although it may be tempting to use the same password if you have more than one online account on different websites, it is far more secure to have a different and unique password for each online account you have. This reduces the chances of all your accounts being accessed if one of your passwords is compromised.

You should also regularly change your password to improve the security of your online account. Similarly, if you ever have any suspicions that someone may have accessed your account, you should immediately change your password.

You can re-set your password on dominos.co.uk or dominos.ie at any time by logging into your MyDomino’s account and selecting the ‘view personal details’ option.

If you've forgotten your password, enter your email address on the 'forgotten your password' page and we'll send you an email. Simply follow the instructions in the email to change your password.

## Phishing

Phishing is the name given to attempts to steal personal details and financial account details from a website user. "Phishers" use fake or "spoof" emails to lead users to counterfeit websites where the user is tricked into entering their personal details, such as credit card numbers, user names and passwords.

If you do receive such an email or are asked for your password by anyone claiming to work for us, please report the incident using our Contact Form or in writing to us at Domino's Head Office, 1 Thornbury, West Ashland, Milton Keynes MK6 4BB, for the attention of the Data Security Manager.

## How to get copies of or amend the information we have collected

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you, please contact us using our Contact Form or write to us at Domino's Head Office, 1 Thornbury, West Ashland, Milton Keynes MK6 4BB for the attention of the Legal Department.

**Please note that we cannot provide you with any information about you held by any of our Franchisees as we do not have access to this information. To obtain a copy of any information held by a Franchisee, you should make a request of the Franchisee directly via your local Store.**

If you think any information we have about you is incorrect or incomplete, please write or email us and we will correct or update any information as soon as possible.

## Linking

We may link to other websites which are not within our control. Once you have left our Sites, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

Any changes we make to this Privacy Policy will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by email. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

## How to Contact Us

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, please contact the Legal Department at Domino’s Head Office, 1 Thornbury, West Ashland, Milton Keynes MK6 4BB.
